var quiz = [{"answers": ["Addition to the endangered species list", "Aerial wolf eradication program", "Addition to the CITES list", "Reintroduction to previous habitats"], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "All of the following were steps to conserve wolves, EXCEPT:"}, {"answers": ["wildfires", "disease", "access to water", "climate"], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "All of the following are examples of abiotic factors that can affect wolves, EXCEPT:"}, {"answers": ["Rewilding has increased biodiversity and promoted better ecosystem functioning.", "Limiting wolves to certain areas negatively affects their genetic pool.", "Not including the voices of all stakeholders involved in wolf management.", "Allowing aerial hunts can have a negative top-down cascade effect on ecosystems."], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "All of the following are problems with current policies regarding wolves, EXCEPT:"}, {"answers": ["Flattery", "Electric fences", "Guard dogs", "Radio collars"], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "In the video watched in class,\u201dKeeping Wolves Out of Harm\u2019s Way\u201d, which of the following was NOT given as a suggestion to protect wolves?"}, {"answers": ["True", "False"], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "Areas designated as wilderness are accessible equally by everyone."}, {"answers": ["Deep ecology", "An ecocentric approach", "Anthropocentrism", "Conservation biology"], "correctIndex": 2, "question": "The rewilding movement incorporates all of the following approaches, EXCEPT:"}, {"answers": ["Bald eagle", "Coyote", "Mountain lion", "Grizzly bear"], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "Which carnivore moved in after wolves were exterminated from Yellowstone, but could not fill their ecological role?"}, {"answers": ["predation", "disease", "competition", "wildfires"], "correctIndex": 3, "question": "All of the following are examples of biotic factors that can affect wolves, EXCEPT:"}, {"answers": ["Additional soil nutrients from decomposing carcass kills.", "Increases in amphibians and reptiles.", "Increased numbers of beavers and their dams.", "Fewer willow trees as elk numbers will decrease."], "correctIndex": 3, "question": "By returning wolves to the wild, biologists might observe all of the following changes to the ecosystem EXCEPT what?"}, {"answers": ["True", "False"], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "The goal of rewilding programs is to promote biodiversity and ecosystem functioning."}, {"answers": ["ecocentrism", "maximum sustainable yield", "the land ethic", "utilitarianism"], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "The rewilding movement is based primarily on an ethics of _______."}, {"answers": ["Their ability to adapt to any situation", "Their biological makeup as an apex predator", "Their ability to produce multiple litters within a pack yearly", "Their interactions with the pack"], "correctIndex": 3, "question": "What do scientists believe is the key to the reproductive success and survival of wolves?"}, {"answers": ["Pollution", "Native species introduction", "Habitat fragmentation", "Human-induced climate change"], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "All of the following are ways that humans have contributed to the extinction crises of many organisms, EXCEPT:"}, {"answers": ["Conservation biology", "Deep ecology", "Ecocentrism", "Ethicism"], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "Which type of thinking mainly asks the questions \u201cwhat should be preserved, and why?\u201d"}, {"answers": ["Survival of the fittest", "Top-down trophic processes", "Bottom-up trophic processes", "Toxic trophosism"], "correctIndex": 2, "question": "If a fungus wipes out a certain type of plant, this will have a cascading effect in the upper trophic levels that can ultimately reduce the numbers of apex predators. This is called what?"}, {"answers": ["True", "False"], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "The current extinction crisis is primarily caused by natural factors."}, {"answers": ["Historical extinction rate", "Background extinction rate", "Extinction rate", "Natural extinction rate"], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "The estimated average rate of species loss over the long term is known as what?"}, {"answers": ["True", "False"], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "Changes in one trophic level can create cascading effects that change other trophic levels."}, {"answers": ["bottom-up predators", "top predators", "top-down predators", "apex predators"], "correctIndex": 3, "question": "What do we call organisms that are at the highest trophic level, meaning that they have no natural predators?"}, {"answers": ["True", "False"], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "Different types of apex predators may coexist in the same ecosystem."}, {"answers": ["Setting out poison.", "Wolf bounties, where hunters were given money for each kill.", "Eradication to increase the numbers of bison for indigenous people.", "Hunts to protect livestock and ranches."], "correctIndex": 2, "question": "Which of the following is NOT a type of wolf extermination campaign waged in the U.S.?"}, {"answers": ["True", "False"], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "Once \"Cinderella\" was kicked out of the Druid wolf pack, her best option was to find a new pack."}, {"answers": ["conservation biology; deep ecology", "deep ecology; ecosystem science", "deep ecology; conservation biology", "ecosystem science; conservation biology"], "correctIndex": 2, "question": "The rewilding movement relies upon the field of _______ to determine what is best for sustainability, and the field of _______ to determine how to make it happen."}, {"answers": ["True", "False"], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "Thanks to conservation and rewilding efforts, wolves have been successfully reintroduced to all of the areas of the Americas that they were previously eradicated from by the 1950s."}, {"answers": ["are detrimental to the healthy functioning of ecosystems.", "threaten the livestock and ranching livelihood.", "have valuable fur.", "frequently attack humans."], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "The main reason that wolves were exterminated from much of their habitat is that wolves"}, {"answers": ["True", "False"], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "The primary goal of natural resource management has always been to include stakeholders at all stages of decision making."}, {"answers": ["Higher; lower", "Lower; higher", "Lower; lower", "Higher; higher"], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "________ trophic levels are consumed by successively _______ trophic levels."}, {"answers": ["It sometimes excludes the public from assessments and decision-making.", "All stakeholders are given an equal voice in decision-making that affects them.", "It is a top-down process, dominated by science and government experts.", "It aims to achieve maximum sustainable yield for a given resource."], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "All of the following statements about natural resource management are true, EXCEPT:"}, {"answers": ["stakeholder participation", "an expert-driven management strategy", "the reintroduction of apex predators", "an ecocentric ethic"], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "The National Environmental Policy Act of 1970 was a major turning point in natural resource management because it requires _______."}, {"answers": ["trophic level", "biodiversity level", "apex", "niche"], "correctIndex": 3, "question": "The ecological role that an organism fills is known as a _______."}]

quizCollection['11'] = quiz
